<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Spotify Artist Network</title><link>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/</link><description>Recent content on The Spotify Artist Network</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data description</title><link>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/data-description/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/data-description/</guid><description>Spotify
The dataset involves a network of artists on Spotify acquired from the Tekore API. They were first taken from several playlists and the network expanded by a depth of 3. All artists should have 20 related artists and those that do not either have corrupt metadata or are obscure and do not have enough data.
90,815 artists Everynoise.com
We also obtained the genre(s) related to each artist by scraping data from everynoise.</description></item><item><title>Louvain Network</title><link>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/louvain-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/louvain-network/</guid><description>You might have to right-click and open in new tab to see the image clearer. The format allows for infinite zoom due to vector graphics.</description></item><item><title>Lyrics Sentiment Analysis</title><link>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/lyrics-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/lyrics-analysis/</guid><description>The text that we analyzed was the taken from the lyrics we were able to tokenize.
We did sentiment analysis on these tokens using the LabMT library which is a list of words that is a given a rating for which represents a negative or positive sentiment. The lower the number is, the more negative that word is, and the higher the number is, the more positive the word is.</description></item><item><title>Sentiment Network</title><link>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/sentiment-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/sentiment-network/</guid><description>The sentiment network is represented by nodes that are colored on a gradient between green, yellow, and red based on if the sentiment of the artist is positive, neutral, or negative respectively. The node is sized by the emotion of the artist, meaning that the greater the absolute value of the sentiment, the larger the size is. This is to represent how emotional the artist&amp;rsquo;s lyrics are and to see trends within the genres.</description></item><item><title>The Spotify Network</title><link>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/genre-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/genre-network/</guid><description>You might have to right-click and open in new tab to see the image clearer. The format allows for infinite zoom due to vector graphics.</description></item><item><title>The Spotify Network Analysis</title><link>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/network-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/network-analysis/</guid><description>The Spotify Network contains 90,815 nodes each representing an artist. An edge is created between the artist and their related artists. There can be multiple edges between the same two artists. Each edge is weighted by the order of the artist on the related artist page. The graph is now a single-edge graph by average parallel edge weights.
The Spotify Artist (Genre) Network
Looking at the Spotify Artist Network network, each color represents a different genre.</description></item><item><title>Word Clouds of Most Relevant Words</title><link>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/word-clouds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://terryho618.github.io/ComSocSci22_Final/word-clouds/</guid><description>To further explore the general sentiment and emotion of genres, we will now look at different word clouds based on ranking of the most relevant lyrics.
The weight scheme is based on BM25 Okapi which is a modified version of the TF-IDF scheme. Put simply, it assigns a weight to each word in a song based on how frequent it is (relevance) and how unique it is (rarity), and then it multiplies these two together.</description></item></channel></rss>